In this video, we are going to see the different types, how to create a stack.
Consider the first case that we create is Stack using their array.
So this is the stack implementation in C and we are going to see it and the exercises, but using Java,
they are the same concept.
But we we are concentrating on that concept on how we deal, how we think, how the algorithm behind
the stack works.
OK.
There is different syntax, but it is OK.
We are we are clarifying everything and see and exercises and Jeff.
OK.
So we define max equals three and and count equal to zero, then creating the stack of curves by creating
an int array called items that contains max that we have.
We have it as a three, as three elements.
We it have three elements at maximum and end, though.
OK.
So in order to create a stack, you can see we need to make a struct stack and it is a containing an
array called items.
And and so there is two items it through things that you should take care about.
Them cause stack.
Creation, if there's an array and there is an integer variable called top type definition and defined
the strike a struct stack as though we are creating a method as we are creating an object of this stack.
Now let's see.
This is the fact that we have created array at zero, array at one and that right at index two.
OK.
And this is the variable that we are creating.
It is in the end refers to minus one.
While we are the second a second way, creating an attack attack using Link, at least we start by making
an at a link list.
So but why we are doing this, why we are making an array and a link at least.
Because linked lists are different from a race, and we have seen this in the previous videos.
And what are the advantages behind that, Ray and that what are the advantages of using the at list
over at night?
But there is a very important thing since armies are not dynamic.
We can't increase the size of the list during run time.
So if we create a stack using array, we should specify the size of this stack and we are not able to
expand it or during runtime.
The solution of dynamic stack is to create a stack using the link, at least.
So you remember our friend link at last?
This is the link at least we have had.
If we insert a new node, we are inserting a new item in the stack.
So if we insert the new item in the stack, the head will be moved and we increase that had by one and
we insert a new node at the beginning.
So if we remove, we need to remove these items from the linked list.
We start from the head, OK, bumping from the hat.
How does this thing and using the linked list works in coding.
We have seen the creation of a stack using array.
We have seen the push and pop methods using the array method way and way.
While we are in the next videos, we are going to see how to push and pull data into a stack, but a
stack created by link.